<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Prateeksha Singh</title>
    <link>http://pratu16x7.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Prateeksha Singh</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 16:44:12 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://pratu16x7.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Belief of a Search System</title>
      <link>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/the-belief-of-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 16:44:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/the-belief-of-systems/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some thoughts/aids/ideas that helped me understand some of the concepts like fundamental to so many things in Information Retrieval, as well as other areas.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hogwarts v2</title>
      <link>http://pratu16x7.com/creations/hogwarts-v2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jun 2021 15:51:45 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pratu16x7.com/creations/hogwarts-v2/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thank You Haptik</title>
      <link>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/thank-you-haptik/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 12:11:44 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/thank-you-haptik/</guid>
      <description>course selection
high med low
assignments
   I have been exceptionally lucky, I got to work with people who are wonderful, and I got to do that while being silly.
  learning fundamental things on how to work, how to learn. Work took a backseat, most of the times what mattered is how you did it.
  Like, I owe most of my personal growth and development in the past 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Gratitude Works</title>
      <link>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/how-gratitude-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 08:39:46 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/how-gratitude-works/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Emergence of Backtracking</title>
      <link>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/emergence_of_backtracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 May 2021 16:14:43 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/emergence_of_backtracking/</guid>
      <description>task list
Even if you&amp;rsquo;re not able to do a task a day, just go through the entire thing, that&amp;rsquo;s the only task. It will keep the project&amp;rsquo;s juices (ideas) flowing in the head.
Or even better, tell it to an imaginary audience.
Or even better, trial visual passes, to remove words (only when you have good understanding of above)
Hill charts, unknowns and knowns. Deep work needed vs. shallow work okay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linkedin for School Children</title>
      <link>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/linkedin-for-school-children/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Apr 2020 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/linkedin-for-school-children/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s quite a novel idea to come up with a social network for children which  allows students from different age groups or similar interests to  interact with each other not bound by their current institutions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solving Polyomino Packing</title>
      <link>http://pratu16x7.com/work/solving-polyomino-packing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pratu16x7.com/work/solving-polyomino-packing/</guid>
      <description>An way to solve the Kaleidoscope Classic, a polynomino packing puzzle with an 8x8 board and 18 checkered pieces, that can be arranged in over billlions of ways, and any single pattern formed can have anywhere from millions to a single solution. Given a pattern, a solution is an arrangement of the pieces, flipped or otherwise, that form the pattern.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kaleidoscope Solver</title>
      <link>http://pratu16x7.com/creations/kaleidoscope-solver/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2019 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pratu16x7.com/creations/kaleidoscope-solver/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is an attempt to make a basic solver for the Kaleidoscope Classic, a polynomino packing puzzle with an 8x8 board and 18 checkered pieces, that can be arranged in over billlions of ways.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Charting for the Modern Web</title>
      <link>http://pratu16x7.com/work/charting-for-the-modern-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 11:22:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pratu16x7.com/work/charting-for-the-modern-web/</guid>
      <description>The Frappe Charts talk presented at RedHat Devconf ‘19 and JsFoo Pune ‘19, expanding on implementation details and the open source journey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating Motivation Driven Learning</title>
      <link>http://pratu16x7.com/work/automating-motivation-driven-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pratu16x7.com/work/automating-motivation-driven-learning/</guid>
      <description>An approach to automate stimulating the right thoughts to inculcate independent learning and spark self-interest thorough projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating Self Learning</title>
      <link>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/automating-self-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/automating-self-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After having discussed some thoughts on &lt;a href=&#34;http://pratu16x7.com/2019/04/25/teaching-with-project-driven-motivation.html&#34;&gt;Teaching Concepts via Project-driven Motivation&lt;/a&gt;, we can now talk about how to go about implementing a system that given the data, does this for us, through a popular approach.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching With Project Driven Motivation</title>
      <link>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/teaching-with-project-driven-motivation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 10:01:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/teaching-with-project-driven-motivation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Making learning more reciprocative through a vision of what it&amp;rsquo;d be like after the learning is complete, is very similar to how good products are designed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autotagging Urls</title>
      <link>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/autotagging-urls/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2019 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/autotagging-urls/</guid>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;The Problem&lt;/strong&gt;: Given a set of URLs of programming learning resources, categorize them based  one or more definative characteristics: language, type of site, stage of learning etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talk Proposal Review Jsfoo 2019</title>
      <link>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/talk-proposal-review-jsfoo-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/talk-proposal-review-jsfoo-2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On request: some thoughts on a proposed talk for JSFoo: &lt;a href=&#34;https://hasgeek.com/jsfoo/2019-coimbatore/proposals/not-everything-can-fit-in-rows-and-columns-iWAwizwbfHoaDmpDBw5iQV&#34;&gt;Not everything can fit in rows and columns&lt;/a&gt; by Ashok Vishwakarma&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Erpnext Desk V2</title>
      <link>http://pratu16x7.com/work/erpnext-desk-v2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Feb 2019 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pratu16x7.com/work/erpnext-desk-v2/</guid>
      <description>Transforming the original iconic ERPNext desk to be a more complete bird’s eye view of everything the full-open source ERP system has to offer, all it’s modules and places therein. Also features a gamified dependency tracking: the places and documents that require another prior activation of some other document(s) are notified to user on access.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elvish Lamp</title>
      <link>http://pratu16x7.com/creations/elvish-lamp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Nov 2018 17:40:19 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pratu16x7.com/creations/elvish-lamp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src=&#34;http://pratu16x7.com/creations/elvish-lamp/elvish_lamp.jpg&#34; style=&#34;
    margin: 0 auto;
    margin-top: 1em;
    width: 80%;
&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A mockery of the lost arts of the residents of &lt;a href=&#34;http://tolkiengateway.net/wiki/Eregion&#34;&gt;Eregion&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Title Slide</title>
      <link>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/title-slide/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Sep 2018 10:00:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/title-slide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Getting around to make a good Open Day title slide is no ordinary feat. Sometimes it’s drab, and sometimes you just get lucky. Here’s a tiny story.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pacman Console</title>
      <link>http://pratu16x7.com/creations/pacman-console/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pratu16x7.com/creations/pacman-console/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A console Pacman game in Python&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marketplace Module</title>
      <link>http://pratu16x7.com/work/marketplace-module/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pratu16x7.com/work/marketplace-module/</guid>
      <description>An in-app interface to ERPNext where existing users can publish their inventory items and discovery others. The items are synced with a central marketplace server, setup as a Frappe instance. The in-app interface itself is dynamic, allowing users to browse items from the server by categories, check details, and message other users for more information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Pre Commit to Manage Git Hooks</title>
      <link>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/using-pre-commit-to-manage-git-hooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 09:59:59 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/using-pre-commit-to-manage-git-hooks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Code-formatting  is the one thing we consistently care about in software. However, it  isn’t a difficult problem to solve these days; with an assortment of  plugins for your favourite editor, you can easily check your code on  save, or even on the fly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing The Docs</title>
      <link>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/writing-the-docs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 16:44:12 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/writing-the-docs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So you’re me and you’re a software dev, and you’re faced with the ultimate task of finally getting around to writing documentation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dear Naniji</title>
      <link>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/dear-naniji/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 09:59:56 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/dear-naniji/</guid>
      <description>It was a book-perfect place in the verandah beyond the doorstep of your old little place in Lower Parel, listening to the stories you would tell us, making clay figures with all the children there, and laughing at the little things you’d get happy over. The little me would wonder what a single visit from us had that you craved so much, no one else would get so very delighted. Time went by and we were able to surprise more than you would surprise us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Erpnext Setup</title>
      <link>http://pratu16x7.com/work/erpnext-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2017 15:12:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pratu16x7.com/work/erpnext-setup/</guid>
      <description>This was a general rewrite to forgo the legacy 9-step Setup Wizard that the first-time users would have to go through even before getting a glimpse of what their newly registered instance looked like. The first stage required only basic personal configuration, setting up with bootstrapped data to initialise the desk. The second would appear as an optional-but-essential wizard once inside, to enable users to import their own data, and guide them through a preliminary accounting flow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Svg Charting Library From Scratch</title>
      <link>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/svg-charting-library-from-scratch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/svg-charting-library-from-scratch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We come across plenty of data scenarios for our ERPNext users. It all  began when we needed them to be able to track sales. It would be nice to  fit in a tiny sales history graph on the user company master of our  product, so we started looking for options.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frappe Charts</title>
      <link>http://pratu16x7.com/creations/frappe-charts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pratu16x7.com/creations/frappe-charts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://frappe.io/charts&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Charts Homepage ➜&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A GitHub-inspired SVG charting library for the web written in  JavaScript. Something I made it while working on analytics for ERPNext in  the Frappe framework. My most popular work yet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking Flight</title>
      <link>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/taking-flight/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2017 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/taking-flight/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some weeks back, our team had organized a code sprint at Kozhikode, one of  the first sprints organised away from our office in Mumbai, and I was  lucky enough to be one of members who were to go. To me, it was going to be a new experience on so many levels, with the first stage being  probably the most exciting of all.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Visit to the Countryside</title>
      <link>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/visit-to-the-countryside/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 09:59:37 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/visit-to-the-countryside/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Trips to our native place in Varanasi have long ceased to be the annual summer visits that they used to be during my school days. Especially for me, they are fewer and farther between than for my parents. This year however, mother and I decided to go for a week’s stay.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Its Details All the Way Down</title>
      <link>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/its-details-all-the-way-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2017 09:59:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/its-details-all-the-way-down/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We  live in a time when like all things, visual story-telling and and art  have evolved not just with creative genius as they used to, but also with technology. But even with the advent of animation that represented  the same number of dimensions as the real world, it wasn’t very common to see stories that weren’t merely a 3D mapping of their caricatured 2D versions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Open Source Meetup</title>
      <link>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/an-open-source-meetup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2017 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/an-open-source-meetup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We were all at the LUG (Linux Users Group) meet-up this weekend, with an  assorted group of programmers, contributors, professors and students  coming together to talk on all things open source. Here are some of the highlights.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning to Build a Game From Scratch</title>
      <link>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/learning-to-build-a-game-from-scratch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/learning-to-build-a-game-from-scratch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few days back, I got a chance to be a part of a team to make something at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://mumbaihackathon.in&#34;&gt;Mumbai Hackathon&lt;/a&gt;. Amidst all the more worldly projects, we had decided on making a game.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Search (Frappe)</title>
      <link>http://pratu16x7.com/work/global-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pratu16x7.com/work/global-search/</guid>
      <description>MySQL based full text search for Frappe’s Awesome bar, in order to allow searching documents not just by name, but content and metadata, with the search fields customisable for different document types.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Greys Masterpiece</title>
      <link>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/greys-masterpiece/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2017 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/greys-masterpiece/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We in general instinctively take a not very positive view of politics. The curated news and media don’t help, and there are enough affairs to back or rebuke nearly every side of the debate about what is right. But  arguably, most systems of power that are stable aren’t always very good  either. So why can’t we have benevolent kings?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming in a Childrens Book</title>
      <link>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/programming-in-a-childrens-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 09:59:13 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/programming-in-a-childrens-book/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@rushabh_mehta/art-in-childrens-books-8cbd74ee0a5?source=post_page---------------------------&#34;&gt;Art in Children’s Books&lt;/a&gt;  talks about the importance of good books (Hurray for Tintin!) when it  comes to making children grasp the wonders of the wide world. But the  (relatively) new field of programming is popularly considered arcane,  partly because it derives from and touches upon so many other domains.  But what gets hidden behind all that detail is that it is actually a way  of thinking, and hence it isn’t generally thought of as something you’d  teach to little kids.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instincts</title>
      <link>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/instincts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2016 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/instincts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had been once asked during an interview, “What is this GitHub profile  that you mention?” referring to the section that occupied most of the  resume. I tried explaining it to them (one of whom was an IITian) on  their laptop as a place where you hosted your code.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ar Piano</title>
      <link>http://pratu16x7.com/work/ar-piano/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pratu16x7.com/work/ar-piano/</guid>
      <description>IJEA 2016 Vol 6 Issue 3 A gesture-controlled portable AR piano, using a webcam and a paper template placed in front of it, which can be played, with accurate separation of strokes at normal playing speeds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hogwarts Castle</title>
      <link>http://pratu16x7.com/creations/hogwarts-v1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 17:40:13 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pratu16x7.com/creations/hogwarts-v1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A fully-detailed, pop-up, light-up miniature of the magical school.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Face Tracker</title>
      <link>http://pratu16x7.com/creations/face-tracker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pratu16x7.com/creations/face-tracker/</guid>
      <description>A program interfacing OpenCV (C++) and an Arduino microcontroller, that identifies a moving object and tracks it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zeal 2015 Website</title>
      <link>http://pratu16x7.com/creations/zeal-2015-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pratu16x7.com/creations/zeal-2015-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My first website. Made for VCET College.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3d Printing</title>
      <link>http://pratu16x7.com/work/3d-printing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2014 11:23:28 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pratu16x7.com/work/3d-printing/</guid>
      <description>A presentation detailing why it is the best thing since sliced bread.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Midnight Magic</title>
      <link>http://pratu16x7.com/creations/midnight-magic/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Mar 2007 12:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pratu16x7.com/creations/midnight-magic/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My very first digital art, made in Gimp.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/belief-of-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pratu16x7.com/stories/belief-of-systems/</guid>
      <description>The Belief of a Search System … and doing the best despite uncertainties
So as it is our last day, I thought to share some thoughts/aids/ideas that helped me understand some of the concepts like fundamental to so many things that we&amp;rsquo;ve been studying. I don&amp;rsquo;t doubt that there would be plenty of mistakes (and dimness in labels) for a first draft, and will be glad to receive any and all corrections and feedback :)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
